## **HWAYOUNG CHOI**

Junior software developer

Phone: 604-379-5693 | e-mail: hy3980@gmail.com | Vancouver, B.C. Github: https://github.com/hy2207 | Website: http://www.hwayoungchoi.com

## **SUMMARY**

Motivated and enthusiastic developer interested in devising a better problem-solving method for challenging tasks. Has a research experience of machine learning, especially, neural engineering during graduate school and published a paper to IEEE. Also, proposed a model for classifying users soft skills with text messages using the Python during the internship. Love coding and learn quickly based on experience in variety of fields.

## **SKILLS**

- Documentation skills: MS Excel, Power Point, Word, LaTeX
- Programming Languages: Java, Python, C#, MATLAB, PHP, JavaScript, Django, Kotlin, Flask
- Database & Other Skill: SQL, MySQL, MongoDB, Tableau, Git
- Math (Statistics and probability)/ Logic and analysis

## **EXPERIENCE**

Sep. 2020 to Nov. 2021	Server
	Daeji cutlet house – Vancouver, B.C
May. 2019 to Sep. 2019	Data Analyst Intern
	Base – Vancouver, B.C
	<ul> <li>Building ML models to analyze personality traits using users' text</li> </ul>
	messages using Python
Jan. 2016 to Feb. 2018	Research Assistant
	Soongsil University – Seoul, S. Korea
	<ul> <li>Principal investigators during research into neural engineering topics.</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Write two papers introduced a novel neural decoding method</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Developed algorithms that can be used by amputee patients by</li> </ul>
	analyzing EMG signal
	Teaching assistant of engineering math
Nov. 2012 to Dec. 2013	Teaching Assistant
	Winners academy – Seoul, S. Korea
	<ul> <li>Tutor secondary school students in math</li> </ul>
EDUCATION	
Jan. 2019 to Jun. 2021	Post Baccalaureate Diploma of Emerging Technology
	Douglas College – New Westminster, B.C
Mar. 2016 to Feb. 2018	Master of Engineering
	Soongsil University – Seoul, S. Korea
	<ul> <li>Major in Neural Signal Processing</li> </ul>
	<ul> <li>Got a scholarship given to promising students in Engineering Dept.</li> </ul>
Mar. 2011 to Feb. 2016	Bachelor of Electronic Engineering Soongsil

University - Seoul, S. Korea